I know without a doubt that I killed [*].
俺はあの時 確かに…を殺した
Nothing will change that fact.
この事実に変わりはない
That's why I decided to come clean here.
だから ここで告白しておこうと決めた
This is my confession.
これが俺の罪の告白だ
It's been two weeks since the trip,
合宿から二週間
and nobody remembers [*]
ever being in the class.
誰一人として…がクラスにいたことを覚えていない
He's been completely forgotten.
忘れちまってるんだ
Only I, the sole person deeply involved
in his death, still remember [*].
…の死と深く関わった俺だけは
まだあいつのことを覚えてる
But I get the feeling it's only a matter of time.
でも それも時間の問題じゃないかって気がする
That's why, while my memory is still clear,
だから 記憶がまだ確かなうちに
I want to tell you the truth,
この事実を
and how to stop the calamity.
どうやったら災厄を止められるかを伝えようと思って
Are you listening?
いいか
Send them back to death, where they belong.
「死者」を死に帰せ
Send the dead back to death.
「死者」を死に帰すんだ
That's how to stop the calamity
once it's begun.
それが 始まってしまった災厄を止める方法だ
Open the eyelid that conceals the night
夜ヲ覆ウ目蓋開ケ
凶キ影ヲ恐レルナカレ
And fear not the evil shadows
I am as a doll
仄くらき柩から
Born from a dusky coffin
産み堕とされた人形のように
With a growing body frozen red
躰は赤く凍え
And a heart soothed by darkness
心は闇にあやされ育つ
Can you see me?
君に僕が見えるかい
My nails steeped in fresh blood
つなぐ手の冷たさに
Sink into the chill of our joined hands
鮮血の爪立てる
Now, let me see you frown
眉寄せてごらんよ
壊し合おう先に続く 謎に満ちる結末を
Let us destroy one another
And face the ending full of mystery that lies ahead
Before we rot away in emptiness
羽も脚ももがれたまま
With our wings and legs ripped away
虚空のなか朽ち果てるより
There is another me
もうひとり僕がいて
Who loves someone so much it hurts
誰かを痛いほど愛しているんだ
I wonder, which one is the illusion?
さぁどっちが幻だろうね
Back in elementary school,
小学生の時
あの子にそっくりな子がいたの
there was a girl who looked just like her.
You mean Misaki?
あの子って 見崎さん
Yes.
そう
But I thought Misaki was an only child.
見崎さん 一人っ子のはずだけど
I wasn't in the same class as her,
同じクラスになったことないけど
but I know people called her Misaki.
「ミサキ」って呼ばれてた
That makes no sense.
おかしいじゃない
From her address,
見崎さんの住所だと
she shouldn't have even been
in the same school as you.
あなたと同じ学校には行かないはずよ
That's exactly why it's so strange.
でしょ
だから変だなって
Did she wear an eyepatch over her left eye?
眼帯は 左目の
No.
してなかった
Our Misaki lost her eye when she was four!
彼女 左目無くしたの 四歳の時だって
What? Then she...
えっ じゃあ あの子
Is the dead person here on this trip?
この合宿に そいつは来てるの
The extra person...
「もう一人」は
is here.
来てる
Who is it?
誰
It's...
それは
Sakaki!
サカキ
I think I might have done something bad!
俺
やっちまったかも
Teshigawara? What happened?
勅使河原
どうしたんだ
お二人さんに質問 いいか
Can I ask you two a question?
What is it?
何だよ いきなり
Do you know a kid named Tomohiko Kazami?
風見智彦ってやつ 知ってるか
What?
Just tell me!
だからさ 聞いてんだよ
Do you know Kazami?
知ってるか 風見のこと
What's he like?
どんなやつだ
Of course I know him.
知ってるも何も
He's a class officer and
the guy you've always been stuck with.
クラス委員長で 勅使河原の腐れ縁だろう
Misaki?
見崎は
How could I not know him?
知らないわけないでしょ
This is bad...
ヤバいよ ヤバいことに
Really bad...
What is?
ヤバいって 何が
間違ったのかも 俺
I think I might have been wrong.
Wrong? About what?
間違った 何を
Well, I...
俺 俺さ
てっきりあいつが「もう一人」だと思ってさ
I was sure he was the extra.
So just now, I...
今先
He was...
あいつって それ
You mean...
Kazami...
風見だよ
You didn't!
まさか
I did!
やっちまったんだよ
You can't be serious.
嘘だろ
Why would I lie about this?!
こんな嘘ついてどうすんだよ
I tried to probe him a little,
あいつに探りを入れてみたんだ
since he's been acting weird lately.
最近 ちょっと様子が変でさ
And he said he didn't remember
the stuff we did together as kids.
そしたらさ がきの頃 一緒にやらかした事を
忘れたって
He didn't remember much
from elementary school either.
小学校の頃の話もよく覚えてないって
And then?
それで
I braced myself, and asked him,
覚悟決めて問いつめたんだよ
"You're not really Kazami, are you?"
「お前はほんとは風見じゃないだろ」
"You're the extra person in
the class, aren't you?!"
「お前がクラスに紛れ込んだもう一人なんだろ」って
He looked panicked at first,
then he flew into a rage.
そしたら あいつすげえおろおろして パニクって
とうとう怒り出して
He was acting so suspiciously,
I was sure it was him.
怪しい
やっぱりこいつだって 俺 思ってさ
So like the tape said, if he died,
if he "returned to death,"
例のテープで言ってたとおり
こいつが死んだら
「死」に帰っちまったら
we'd all be saved.
それで皆助かるんだって
Don't tell me...
まさか
you killed him?
殺した
Did you?
本当
I didn't mean to do it!
はっきり殺そうと思ってたわけじゃ
We started grappling and ended up
outside, on the balcony.
掴み合いになって 外のべランダに出て
気がついたら そこから
And the next thing I knew...
He was lying still on the ground below.
あいつ 地面に倒れて動かなくて
Blood was coming from his head.
頭から血も出てて
それで俺怖くなって
I got scared,
and ran back down the hall.
廊下に飛び出して
I'd seen Sakaki come in here earlier.
ここに 先サカキがこの部屋に入るの見えたから
So, you wanted to find out
if Kazami was the extra?
確認だったのか
風見くんが「もう一人」だったのかって
Yeah...
ああ 「もう一人」が死んじまったら
I thought, if the extra died,
その直後から もうそいつはいなかったことになるって
it would be as if he'd never existed.
But you two said you know him,
けど お前らは風見を知ってるって
so I must have been wrong!
やっぱり間違ったのか 俺
Tell me, Sakaki, was I wrong?
な サカキ どうなんだよ
Either that, or he's not dead.
間違えたか 死んでないのかも
Huh?
Falling from two stories up
wouldn't necessarily kill him.
二階の高さなら 死ぬとは限らないだろ
You can't see where he fell from here.
ここからは見えないな
It's past that row of shrubs.
あの植え込みの向こう
The first thing we should do
is check if he's alive.
とにかくまず 風見くんが生きてるかどうか確かめよう
O... Okay...
Maejima, what happened to you?!
前島くん どうしたの
Blood?
血
ダメだ もう
I can't...
Oh, no.
まさか 刺された
Were you stabbed?
I looked in the dining hall.
食堂を 覗いたら
Th... The manager...
か 管理人が
The manager?
管理人さん
Maejima, we've gotta get out of here!
前島くん 逃げないと
Why are you screaming, Kouichi?
ない騒いでるの 恒一くん
Sakaki, what's going on?
サカキ どうしたんだよ
Who is that?
誰なの
It's Maejima!
前島くんだよ
He's hurt!
ケガをしてるんだ
How?
何でよ
He's been stabbed!
刺されてるんだ
And there's a fire in the dining hall!
それに 食堂から火が
A fire?
火事
The manager's inside, dead.
中で管理人さんが死んでるだ
He was murdered.
殺されてるんだ
The killer must have started the fire.
きっとその犯人が火を
Are you serious?!
マジかよ
It won't work.
ダメか
Did you find Kazami?
風見くんは
He's gone.
いねえんだよ
Was that Takako?
今の 多佳子
Sugiura!
杉浦さん
You, get Maejima someplace safe,
あんたは前島くんを安全なところまで運んで
and call 119!
119番
Right.
はい
That room...
この部屋
It's mine, and Takako's.
私と多佳子の部屋
多佳子 いる
Takako, are you in here?
Oh, no, Takako!
まさか 多佳子
Takako, where are you? Takako!
多佳子 どこなの
多佳子
Sakakibara?
榊原くん
What's going on?
何が
Have you seen Sugiura or Kazami?
杉浦さんと風見くん 見なかった
I saw Kazami.
風見くんなら
He came to my room, covered with mud
and his face clouded in anger,
ちょっと前 泥だらけで血相変えて部屋にやってきて
saying Teshigawara was acting weird.
「勅使河原がおかしい」って
Huh?
I asked what happened,
何があったんだって
but he just glared daggers at me.
すごいけんまくで
So I mentioned the tape...
それで あのテープのことを
You told him?
話した
Yeah...
He's not in here?
いないか
It's gone!
ない
The tape recorder's gone!
テープレコーダーがないよ
What? Why?
えっ 何で
Sakaki!
サカキ
Is Kazami here?
風見は
How's Maejima?
前島くんは
I left him with someone who heard
the screams and ran in to help.
悲鳴聞いて飛び出して来たやつに任せた
Guys...
ねえ
What's going on?
一体何が起こってるの
Let's split up and look for Kazami.
手分けして風見くんを探そう
And stop by all the rooms
and tell everyone to get out.
後部屋を回って皆に逃げるように
There's a fire! Get out of here!
火事だぞ 逃げろ
Huh?
えっ 火事
A fire?
A killer?
えっ 人殺し
Somewhere in this building.
この建物にいるんだよ
Plus, there's a fire in the dining hall,
おまけに 食堂に火がついてるらしいし
and we don't know where Kazami went.
風見もどこ行ったか分かんねえしよ
Everything's so messed up!
もう めちゃくちゃだ
三神先生に伝えないと
We have to tell Ms. Mikami.
Ms. Mikami, are you there?
先生 三神先生
We're coming in.
入りますよ
いねえじゃん
She's gone.
あれ 血だよね
Is that blood?
Yeah...
だな
You don't suppose something
happened to Ms. Mikami, do you?
もしかして 三神先生に何か
あ あのよ 外出て警察呼んだほうがよくねえか
Don't you think we should go outside
and call the police?
No!
ダメだよ
Not before we make sure Ms. Mikami is okay.
三神先生の無事を確かめないと
Ms. Mikami?
先生
Who was that?
今の
Teshigawara.
勅使河原
And Mochizuki.
と望月くんね
It came from downstairs, right?
下からだったよね
Let's check it out.
行ってみよう
Found you.
いた
Takako!
多佳子
Are you okay?
大丈夫なの
Thank goodness.
よかった
If you had died too,
泉美まで死んじゃったら
I couldn't go on.
私生きていけない
Just like you can't live without me.
泉美は私がいないと
Takako?
多佳子
Send the dead back to death!
「死者」を死に
イテッ
Ow!
Teshigawara, let's get out of here!
勅使河原くん 逃げよう
M... My leg...
足
Send the dead back!
死に返す
Stop!
Send the dead back!
やめろ
Out of my way!
邪魔するな
She said, "Send the dead back to death."
「死者」を死に返すって
How did she know about that?
何で杉浦さんが
She listened to the tape.
あの子 聞いたから テープ
You found it in the old
Class 3 homeroom, right?
昔の三組で見つけたんでしょう
Ogura told me.
小椋から聞いた
We're looking for a clue to
stopping the calamity.
災厄を止める手がかりを探しに来たんだ
Seriously?
えっ マジ
I see.
そうか
The tape was brought here?
テープはここで
Yes, by Mochizuki.
そう 望月くんにね
As the head of countermeasures,
I had to listen to it.
対策係として 聞かないわけにはいかなかった
But why does she think
Misaki is the dead person?
でも どうして見崎が「死者」だなんて
Ever since our trip to the beach,
Takako's been emotionally unstable.
多佳子 海から帰ってきて
精神的にかなり変調起き出してて
I'm going to look for her.
私 多佳子を探してくる
No, Akazawa!
It's too dangerous to go alone!
赤沢さん 一人じゃ危ない
This is an important message
対策係から
from the head of countermeasures
to the students of Class 3.
三組の皆さんに大事なお知らせです
The tape you are about to hear
これからお聞かせするテープは
was left behind fifteen years ago,
when the calamity stopped midyear.
十五年前途中で災厄が止まった年に残されたテープです
どうやったら災厄を止められるかを伝えようと思って
...and how to stop the calamity.
Are you listening?
いいか
Send them back to death, where they belong.
「死者」を死に返せ
Send the dead back to death.
「死者」を死に返すんだ
That's how to stop the calamity
once it's begun.
それが始まってしまった災厄を止める方法だ
These are the facts.
事実
The calamity was stopped midyear,
fifteen years ago.
十五年前災厄は途中で止まりました
And the dead person this year is...
そして 今年の「死者」は
Mei Misaki.
見崎鳴です
I know this because we went to
the same elementary school,
なぜなら
私は小学生の頃
左目をなくしていない見崎さんと 同じ学校だったのです
and her left eye was intact.
Yet now, she is missing her left eye.
なのに 今の彼女は左目をなくしている
What does this mean?
どういうことでしょう
That she was reborn incomplete.
それは 不完全な復活をしたからです
The Mei Misaki we know is a fake.
今の見崎鳴は偽物です
And that's why we must...
ですから
kill her!
殺す
No!
違う
Return the dead...
「死者」を死に
...to death.
死に返せ
Return the dead...
「死者」を
Stop this!
やめなさい
Ms. Mikami!
三神先生
You can't kill your own classmate!
クラスメートを殺すなんて ダメよ
But if we send the dead person back to death,
「死者」を死に返せば
no one else will have to die!
誰も死ななくなるんですよ
If we kill Misaki, the calamity will end!
見崎を殺せば 災厄は止まるんです
No!
違う
Don't do this! You're making a mistake!
違うわ ダメよ
Then who the hell's dead?!
じゃあ 「死者」は誰なんですか
それは
I don't know.
But...
でも
I... I...
僕は 死にたくないんだ
I don't want to die!
No!
ダメ
You bastard!
こいつ
Asshole!
てめえ
There!
いた
The dead girl!
There!
「死者」だ
I'll avenge my brother!
兄貴の仇
No!
違う
You...
No!
ころっ
I'm sorry!
ごめん
Open up!
開けろ
Damn it...
くそ
Move!
退け
滑るから 気を付けて
Careful, it's slippery.
There you are!
いた
Send the dead back to death!
「死者」を死に
Ogura!
小椋
廊下出たぞ
They're in the hallway!
We're sav...
助かっ
下から回り込め
Go in from downstairs!
You really think it's Misaki?
ホントに見崎さんなのかな
There's something off about her.
あの女は怪しいっつうな
I know, but...
そうだけどさあ
Something smells burnt.
何か 焦げ臭いな
He did say there was a fire.
火事だって 言ってたよね
I don't see any flames though.
火は見えてねえけどな
The dining hall?
食堂か
We should be safe here.
ここは大丈夫そうだね
I think it's stopped.
収まったね
What on earth happened?
一体どうしたの
An explosion in the dining hall, probably.
たぶん 食堂で爆発が起きたんだ
Oh...
そう
Maejima passed out in front
of the dining hall.
食堂の前で倒れてた前島くんって
Could Sugiura have...
もしかして杉浦さんが
It wasn't me.
私じゃないよ
It was probably that old crone.
たぶん あのババア
Crone?
ババアって
You...
あなた
are in my way!
邪魔
But I won't kill you,
since you're not the dead one.
でも「死者」じゃないから殺しはしない
Besides, Izumi seems fond of you.
泉美のお気に入りだしね
「死者」を死に
Send the dead back to death!
Damn you!
Why...
何で
Why is this happening?
何で こんなことに
Kouichi?
恒一くん
Akazawa!
赤沢さん
えっ 誰 それ
Who is that?
Takako!
多佳子
Mei Misaki...
見崎 鳴
You really are...
あんた やっぱり
No, Akazawa!
違うんだ
赤沢さん
Sugiura was...
杉浦さんは
I'll kill you!
殺してやる
If the dead person was gone...
「死者」はいなくなれば
all of these tragic things...
こんな悲しいことも
would stop, right?
止まるはずよね
見崎
Misaki?
Misaki!
見崎
Like film that loses its color with time
色褪せてく フィルムのように
The now that we know will one day fade
確かな今も いずれ霞んで
That fleeting moment's light
何でもなく 笑いあった
When we shared a laugh over nothing
刹那の時間と光
繋がってゆく 記憶の底に
It now lies, waiting to be found, at the depths
Of memories that connect one to the next
誰かが見つけるためあると信じてる 今でも
This I still believe
"Stand by oneself"